Welcome
For this coding challenge, we are given two strings.
-a main string-
-and a target string.
Our goal is to find the smallest section of the main
string that contains all the characters in the target string.
To do this, we will code a sliding window
that dynamically adjusts its boundaries, while using a hashmap
to keep track of the elements within the window
We start by setting a left pointer that tracks the start of our window
And a right pointer that tracks the end
For any window to be viable as a sub-string, it
must contain all the characters of the target string.
So, we create a hashmap to store the
counts of the characters in our target string
And a hashmap to store the counts of the characters in our window
We start by expanding our window to the
right until it contains all the target characters.
Once our window contains all the target characters, it
becomes a viable substring. So, we stop expanding, and
record it as the minimum sub-string we have found.
Then, to see whether we can make it any smaller, we begin
to shorten the window from the left, removing characters one by one.
After each contraction, we check to see if the window is
still viable, and if it's the smallest window so far.
Once our window no longer contains all the target letters, it is
no longer viable, and we stop contracting. Then, we begin to expand
again towards the right to find the next viable window.
Once the window becomes viable again, we stop expanding. We check
the string to see if it's smaller than the minimum. Then,
we begin to shorten the window from the left again.
Once again, at every round, we check to see
whether our window is the smallest found so far.
And record it if it is.
And once our window is again no longer viable, we
stop contracting and expand to the right once more
Finally, we reach the end of the
string. Since our final window is non-viable-
-we return the value of our smallest substring and end the program.
If you'd like to see how these
steps are coded, please continue to watch